On the first page of the sentence, the one you
en la primera página de la sentencia la
are putting in Thai there,
que estás poniendo en tailandés ahí
apart from putting the name of his master, the
aparte de poner el nombre de su maest el
king's court of the province of Cosam Mu
rey tribunal de la provincia de cosam mu
and such, the prosecutor as plaintiff,
y tal el fiscal como demandante la señor
Mr. Leosbaldo José Arrieta Nieves and
el señor leosbaldo José Arrieta nievez y
Mrs. Ana Marcela Arteaga, as if they
la señora Ana Marcela Arteaga como que
join the lawsuit against the gentleman and
se unen a la demanda contra el señor y
what it says comes to say the first
lo que dice viene a decir la primera
page says subject crime against life
página dice sujeto delito contra la vida
crime against officials in the
delito contra los funcionarios en
administration of Justice It is reported
administraciones de Justicia Se informa
that he has committed a violation of the law
que ha cometido una violación de la ley
in several different crimes that occurred on
en varios delitos diferentes que ocurrió
August 2, 2023 between day and
el 2 de Agosto de 2023 entre el día y la
night the time is not Clara the accused to
noche la hora no está Clara el acusado a
kill with intent of premeditation for
matar con intención de premeditación por
a plan to kill using force
un plan de matar utilizando la fuerza
to end the life of Mr.
para acabar con la vida del señor
Arrieta Artiaga, that says the first
Arrieta Artiaga eso dice la primera
page of the sentence José has seen
página de la sentencia José ha visto muy
the sentence's composition very different from
diferente la sentencia la composición
the Spanish sentences
que tiene a las sentencias españolas Es
The Spanish sentence is that I
que la sentencia españolas es que os
tell you one thing Now when
digo una cosa Ahora cuando empiece a
this starts to move, I advise the defense and
moverse esto yo aconsejo a la defensa y
the prosecution and everyone to
a la acusación y a todo el mundo que se
look for someone Thai because it is a
busque alguien tailandés porque es un
hodgepodge.  I've been
batiburrillo yo llevo toda la tarde
calling tuyupa all afternoon, you know why because it
Llamando a tuyupa ya lo sabes porque es
's such a mess, you don't
que es un batiburrillo no sabes
really know what he's referring to,
realmente A qué se está refiriendo
so there are going to be people, I'm almost sure
entonces va haber gente estoy cas seguro
that they're going to confuse Daniel's statement
que va a confundir la declaración de
as a proven fact, for example,
Daniel como un hecho probado por ejemplo
they're going to say that it's a proven fact
van a decir que eso es hecho probado
when it's Daniel's statement. I know what's
cuando es la declaración de Daniel yo s
going to happen. He's mixing up
que va a pasar está mezclando
Daniel's statements and also the
declaraciones de Daniel y también los
facts, as if it were a summary of the
hechos Como si fuese un sumario los
facts. So he's already mixing things up
hechos Entonces ya está mezclando cosas
that people, perhaps because Daniel lied on
que la gente quizá porque Daniel menti
several occasions, obviously, but of
varias ocasiones evidentemente pero
course, if people don't understand, they think that's how it is. We'll
claro si la gente no entiende piensa que
start on page 13, okay,
es así empezamos por la página 13 vale
that's where his statement is.
que es donde está la declaración de él
The first thing is complaints. And that's the
lo primero que es denuncias Y eso lo
first thing is the exposition of the
primero son la exposición de los
ap có denounce and so on. Exactly. Yes. It tells
ap có denuncian y demás Exacto Sí Cuenta
the facts and so on. No. And on page 13, starting
los hechos y demás no Y la 13 a partir
on page 13, the
de la página 13 se empieza a recoger el
testimony of Daniel Sancho begins to be collected. The first thing it
testimonio de Daniel Sancho lo primero
says is that it was discovered that the accused and
que dice se descubrió que el acusado y
his partner traveled to Thailand in
su pareja viajaron a Tailandia en el año
2018, of course. You read that and what I
2018 claro Tú lees eso y yo lo que
understand as tuyupa is that the first thing I
entiendo como tuyupa que lo primero que
did was call  tuyupa tuyupa here it
hice fue Llamar a tuyupa tuyupa aquí
says 2018 right and it says fallen with his
pone 2018 verdad Y pone caído con su
partner right yes yes well we imagine
pareja verdad sí sí pues imaginamos
tuyupa And I that it would be with his
tuyupa Y yo que sería con su novia
previous girlfriend who traveled to Thailand in 2018
anterior que viajó a Tailandia en 2018
is what we wanted to understand
es lo que lo que hemos querido entender
because he meets ewin in 2022 I mean he
porque a ewin lo conoce en 2022 O sea no
has nothing to do with ewin and decides to
tiene nada que ver con ewin y decide
establish a restaurant business in
Establecer un negocio de restaurantes en
Thailand that already seems strange to you well
Tailandia eso ya te parece extraño bueno
this This is what Daniel testifies
esta Esto es lo que Daniel testifica
okay we read in one go it is discovered that the
vale leemos del tirón se descubre que el
accused and his partner traveled to Thailand
acusado y su pareja viajaron a Tailandia
in 2018 and decided to establish a
en el año 2018 y decidió Establecer un
restaurant business in Thailand
negocio de restaurantes en Tailandia por
so he booked a
lo que reservó un billete de avión de
round trip plane ticket between July 30, 23
ida y vuelta entre el 30 de julio del 23
and August 23, 23 of course This does not
y el 23 de agosto del 23 claro Esto no
hold up much because from the 18th to the 23rd are
se sostiene mucho porque del 18 al 23
years not July 30, 2023 The
llan años no el 30 de julio de 2023 El
accused arrived at the subar
acusado llegó al aeropuerto de subar
abumi airport the same day the accused on his
abumi el mismo día el acusado un su
trip to the cangan district that is
viaje hacia el distrito de cangan eso es
false I say this because it is recorded
falso lo digo porque está recogido las
on the cameras that it is false in  the province of
cámaras que es falso en la provincia de
suratan at approximately 12 noon
suratan Aproximadamente a las 12 horas
the accused rented a motorcycle for
el acusado alquiló una motocicleta por
a period of 10 days presenting his
un periodo de 10 días presentando su
passport and providing a
pasaporte y proporcionando un número de
contact phone number to the
teléfono de contacto al propietario del
business owner then the accused moved to the
negocio luego el acusado se trasladó al
piman resort hotel where the victim had
hotel piman Resort donde la víctima hab
reserved a room the accused
reservado una habitación el acusado se
checked into the hotel providing his first
registró en el hotel proporcionando su
name surname and a contact phone number
nombre apellidos y un número de teléfono
subsequently the accused
de contacto posteriormente el acusado
continued a tourist trip okay let's go to
continuó un viaje turístico vale vamos a
14 says on august 1st 23 he reserved the
14 dice el 1 de agosto del 23 reservó la
room at the bugin villa hotel from
habitación en el hotel bugin Villa desde
august 1st to august 4th
el 1 de agosto hasta el 4 de agosto
because the aforementioned hotel has
debido a que el hotel mencionado tiene
separate rooms and has
las habitaciones separadas y dispone de
a kitchen for
una cocina para la para la preparación
food preparation where
de alimentos donde se pueden grabar
videos related to cooking can be recorded to
vídeos relacionados con la cocina para
publish them on a youtube channel
publicarlos en un canal de YouTube lo
which the defendant has been doing
cual el demandado ha estado haciendo
for approximately 2 years so that is that he has been
durante aproximadamente 2 años o sea que
publishing videos on youtube for 2 years
lleva 2 años publicando vídeos en
however the aforementioned hotel does
YouTube sin embargo el hotel mencionado
not have the necessary equipment for
no cuenta con el equipo necesario para
food preparation so he will
preparación de alimentos por lo que se
move to a place near the bicc in
trasladará a un lugar cercano al bicc en
the copan gan branch where he
la sucursal de copan Gan donde con
bought a knife garbage bags
compró un cuchillo bolsas de basura
gloves disposable files and various fruits and
guantes files tirables y varias frutas
then return to the hotel  pma res on
para luego regresar al hotel pma res el
August 2, 2023 the accused went
2 de agosto del 23 el acusado se dirigió
to the Lim Pinong Hmart store to
a la tienda lim pinong hmart para
buy a kitchen knife as well as
comprar un cuchillo de cocina así como
kitchen utensils for preparing
utensilios de cocina para preparar
food knife board eh Saw The
alimentos cuchillo tabla eh Sierra El
accused drove a motorcycle to
acusado condujo una motocicleta para
pick up the victim at
recoger a la víctima en el muelle de
Cangan pier The accused told the victim
cangan El acusado le dijo a la víctima
that he was not staying at the
que no se estaba quedando en el hotel
Piman Hotel then the accused took the
piman luego el acusado llevó a la
victim to the Bugin Ville Hotel now comes
víctima al hotel bugin Ville ahora viene
the crux of the matter okay Now we
el mejunje de la cuestión vale Ahora nos
get into fa While the accused and
metemos ya en fa Mientras que el acusado
the victim were in the room
de la víctima estaban en la habitación
the victim was sitting at the end of the
la víctima estaba sentada al final de la
bed and the accused was sitting on the
cama y el acusado estaba sentada en la
bed with the deceased They were both
cama con el fallecido se estaban los dos
sitting on the bed and chatting about
sentados en la cama y conversaron sobre
financial matters in which the
asuntos financieros en los que el
deceased had offered to help him
fallecido se había ofrecido ayudarlo
says that he and Edwin were talking
dice que estuvieron conversando él y
about financial matters no the
Edwin de asuntos financieros no el
accused asked him to record a video
acusado le pidió para grabar un vídeo
for a YouTube advertisement and the
para un anuncio en YouTube y el
deceased said that he had no
fallecido dijo que no tenía intención
real intention of helping him but only wanted to
real de ayudarlo sino que solo quería
have a sexual relationship with him the
tener una relación sexual con él el
accused told the deceased that he did not
acusado le dijo al fallecido que no
have those thoughts that that was his
tenía esos pensamientos que esa era su
idea no the accused had no
idea no el el acusado no tenía ninguna
relationship with the deceased but the
relación con el fallecido pero el
accused needed financial help  of the
acusado necesitaba ayuda financiera del
deceased the deceased said that if he
fallecido el fallecido dijo que si
wanted him to help him with the
quería que le ayudase con el asunto
financial matter the accused would have to use
financiero el acusado tendría que usar
his mouth to perform fellatio on him there is
su boca para hacerle una felación hay
a page 38 39 when the police said
una página 38 39 cuando la policía dijo
that everything he said was a lie on
que todo eso lo que é dijo era mentira
his part, all made up, all to
de él todo inventado todo para
discredit the victim, the accused did not
desacreditar a la víctima el acusado no
agree and threw the deceased
estuvo de acuerdo y echó al fallecido
out of the room, the deceased
fuera de la habitación el fallecido se
approached the accused and attempted to have
acercó a la acusado e intentó tener
sexual relations with the accused and
relaciones sexuales con el acusado y le
threatened her that if she did not accept, he would reveal the
amenazó que si no aceptaba revelaría la
relationship between the deceased and the accused
relación entre el fallecido y el acusado
to other people, but the accused did not
a otras personas Pero el acusado no
accept, the deceased tried to strangle
aceptó el fallecido intentó estrangular
the accused Daniel does not have any marks
al acusado Daniel no tiene ninguna marca
on his neck but he says that he tried to
en el cuello pero él dice que intentó
strangle him okay we just said
estrangularlo vale que acabamos de decir
that Daniel was also taken for a
que Daniel también lo llevaron a un
physical examination and he did not have any of those
examen físico y no tenía nada de esa
marks, the face tried to strangle the
marca el facido intentó trangular al
accused, so the accused
acusado por lo que el acusado le dio un
punched the deceased in the
puñetazo al fallecido en la zona del
face, the deceased stepped back,
rostro el fallecido retrocedió
stumbling, he did not knock him down but he
tropezando tropezó no lo tiró él sino
tripped on the edge of the
que tropezó este con el borde de la
bathroom door, in other words, he no longer fell because of
puerta del baño o sea ya no se cayó por
the blow but from the punch the other  he
el golpe sino que del puñetazo el otro
tripped and fell and he admits that he
se tropezó y cayó y reconoce que él le
hit him first by Razo not Jose but that he does
pega el primer por Razo no José pero que
n't fall to the ground from the blow but rather he
no cae al suelo por el golpe sino que
falls to the ground because he trips,
cae al suelo porque se tropieza sigo
well he made him fall and his head
bueno hizo que se cayese y su cabeza
hit the bathroom counter, the
golpeara El mostrador del lavabo el
defendant approached the deceased and told him
acusado se acercó al fallecido y le dijo
that he didn't like him leaving his
que no le gustaba que se saliese de su
room, that's when noot is
habitación eso ya cuando noot está
lying on the floor to hit him, yeah, of course,
tirado en el suelo a pegar por Sí claro
the defendant bit the victim's left arm
el acusado mordió el brazo izquierdo de
so the defendant hit the
la víctima por lo que el acusado golpeó
deceased's face again, the
nuevamente la cara del fallecido la
victim
víctima
bit him, the defendant tried to hit the
mordus el acusado intent empar a la
victim, he approached to bite his neck
víctima acercó para morderle el cuo
, of course, let's see if he's lying on the floor, the other one is fighting, you don't like
luego se fue para morder en el cuello
it, how he got up bra, he got up, bit one arm then the other arm and then he went to bite his neck. That after having tried, my goodness, I see it as a bit of juggling, no, I mean, imagining myself in my
malabares no O sea imaginándome yo en la
head of the scene, you get up after
cabeza de la escena te levantas después
you've fallen on the floor, you've hit yourself
de que te has caído en el suelo te has
and you do this to bend down
dado un golpe y haces así para agacharte
to bite him but it's not classroom anymore  of
para morderle pero ya no es aula de
glass because then he is in a good
cristal porque entonces él está de buen
mood he travels with him and meets
rollo él viaja con él y se encuentra con
The glass cage in the bungalow does not
La jaula de cristal en el bungaló no
speak of Glass cage because he did not
habla de Jaula de cristal porque él no
feel harassed, that is, according to here in
se sentía acosado o sea según aquí de
fact he did not know that or that Edwin
hecho él no sabía ni que ni que Edwin
wanted a sexual relationship with him, that is what he
quería una relación sexual con él es lo
had a financial business Then the
que tenía un negocio financiero Entonces
thing with Chiqui, that I am not good for biting
lo de Chiqui eso yo no bueno para morder
the accused in the neck the accused
en el cuello al acusado el acusado
pushed the victim who fell and
empujó a la víctima quien cayó y se
collapsed which caused the victim's head to
desplomó lo que hizo que la cabeza de la
hit the sink counter again
víctima golpeara nuevamente el mostrador
the victim began to
del lavago la víctima comenzó a
convulse he understood that it was possible
convulsionar entendió que era posible
that the accused would die and he sat on
que el acusado muriese y estuvo sentado
the bed for hours because he
en la cama durante horas porque se
felt guilty So he used a
sentía culpable Así que usó un arma
knife that he bought at the store in
blanca que se compró en la tienda in
Pimpón J mar and with it he could not cut
Pimpón J mar y con ella no pudo cortar
the victim's clothes he said that he
la ropa de la víctima él dijo que él
felt alone for an hour and to begin with yaar he
sentio solo una hora y para empezar yaar
could not cut the victim's clothes
no pudo cortar la ropa de la víctima por
so he used scissors to cut
lo que utilizó unas tijeras para cortar
the deceased's clothes the victim's body was
la ropa del fallecido el cuerpo de la
found under the
víctima se encontraba debajo del
sink in the bathroom and he used the
fregadero en el baño y utilizó el
aforementioned knife to cut the
cuchillo mencionado para cortar las
victim's wrists and thus prevent
muñecas de la víctima y así evitar que
too much blood from coming out  and
saliese demasiada sangre y lo decapitó
the victim decapitated him by cutting the bones that's what he
la víctima cortando los huesos eso es lo
says but he couldn't So he used the
que dice pero no pudo Así que usó la
saw to cut the deceased's body parts
sierra para cortar las partes del cuerpo
put them in a
del difunto los metió en una bolsa de
plastic bag and went to buy a kayak
plástico y fue a comprar un kayat
depositing 000 to the owner of the kayak
depositando 000 al propietario del kayat
and then returning to the room to
y luego regresando a la habitación para
collect the pieces and now we are going to know
[__] las piezas y ahora vamos a saber
now we are going to understand Why do
ahora vamos a entender Porque esta parte
I believe this part Why doesn't Daniel throw
sí me la creo Por qué Daniel no lo tira
everything into the sea and we have always said
todo al mar y siempre hemos dicho Por
Why does he throw some parts into the sea and
qué se pone tirar unas partes al mar y
others in the garbage Okay then Now you are going to
otras al basurero Vale pues Ahora Vais a
see why he stops throwing
ver por qué deja de tirar partes del
body parts Arm mal now I am going to explain it he
cuerpo Arm mal ahora lo voy a explicar
got on the boat and stopped to
montó en el barco y se detuvo para dejar
drop the parts on the beach but the
caer las partes en la playa pero el
accused reported that a storm broke out
acusado informó que se desató una
so the accused returned to
tormenta por lo que el acusado regresó a
his room again and drove his
su habitación nuevamente y condujo su
motorcycle to take the
moto ceta para tomar las partes del
deceased's body parts and throw them around the
cuerpo de fallecido y arrojarlas por la
island or in other words Hub a storm he stopped
isla o sea como Hub una tormenta dejó de
taking body parts to the sea because of the
llevar partes del cuerpo al mar por la
storm he returned to his room on
tormenta volvió a habitación el 3 de
August 3, 23 at approximately 5 in
agosto del 23 Aproximadamente a las 5 de
the afternoon the accused put
la tarde el acusado metió partes del
body parts in a backpack and  He went to the
cuerpo en una mochila y se dirigió a la
beach then got into a kayak and paddled
playa luego se subió a un kayak y remoar
inside throwing the victim's body parts
adentro arrojando las partes del cuerpo
into the sea with a knife from the
de la víctima al mar con un cuchillo del
aforementioned hotel after that the
Hotel mencionado después de eso el
accused went to the Pan Man
acusado se dirigió al hotel pan Man
Resort hotel to use the facilities
Resort para usar las instalaciones
after that he went to the
después de eso se dirigió al hotel al
Lantara hotel to have lunch then he forgot a
lantara para comer luego olvidó una
black bag and returned to the
bolsa de color negro y regresó al hotel
Bugin hotel to go for a walk on the beach
bugin para salir a pasear Por la playa
feeling a little nervous the
sintiéndose un poco nervioso los
relatives of the deceased sent him
familiares del fallecido le enviaron
messages on August 4, 23 at 1
mensajes al 4 de agosto del 23 a la 1 de
p.m. He says that they sent him the
la tarde Dice que le mandaron los
messages No if I'm not mistaken No that's what he
mensajes No si no me equivoco No eso
says he invited a friend to go to the Futar
dice invitó a ir a una amiga hasta la
police station here where she
comisaría de policía de futar acá donde
met the police officer
se encontró con el oficial de policía
Tosc says the police hired a
tosc dice la policía contrató a un
translator to translate and asked him to
traductor para que tradujo y le pidió
take a photograph please
que tomara fotografía por favor
make sure you take off your clothes and
asegúrese de quitarse la ropa y
make sure that the
asegúrese de que el personal de
inspection personnel are available to
inspección esté disponible para
provide you with a lawyer but the
proporcionarle un abogado pero el
officer or rather he told him that he wanted a
oficial o sea él le dijo que quería un
lawyer but the police officer
abogado pero el oficial de policía le
informed him that it was not a question of
informó que no se trataba de un
questioning a suspect but only
interrogatorio sospechoso sino que solo
a consultation Regarding the matter of a
de una consulta Sobre el asunto de una
person  Missing person says that the
persona desaparecida dice que le dijo el
police officer told him that he did not need a lawyer because
policía que no necesitaba abogado porque
what he was going to do was a has not yet
lo que iba a hacer era una todavía no ha
been charged, that is, he was a witness, he did not
sido acusado o sea era testigo no se
contact the lawyer and the
comunicó al abogado y el oficial de
police officer took him directly upon arriving
policía lo llevó directamente al llegar
at the Bugay Villa Hotel, the accused informed
al hotel bugay Villa el acusado informó
that he would help search for his friend, the
que ayudaría a buscar a su amigo el
police officer detained the
oficial de policía retuvo la motocicleta
accused's motorcycle and phone at around
y el teléfono del acusado alrededor de
9 in the morning, the
las 9 de la mañana el personal del
evidence center staff arrived at the aforementioned hotel, the
centro de pruebas llegó al hotel
English-speaking police officer told the accused that he would
hablaba inglés le dijo al acusado que le
help him search for his
ayudaría a buscar a su amigo
missing friend, the accused requested that
desaparecido el acusado solicitó que
another person and a lawyer be
hubiese otra persona y un abogado
present, the investigation office staff did
presente el personal de la oficina de
not want to make the
investigación no querían hacer que la
situation stressful and
situación fuese estresante y se
promised to follow orders, the
comprometieron a seguir las órdenes El
police officer sent the accused for
oficial de policía envió al acusado a
a medical examination at the hospital,
realizar un examen médico al hospital se
the accused was taken to the
llevó al acusado a la estación de
pstat rak control station where
control de pstat rak donde se realizó la
collection of work-related documents was carried out
recolección de documentos relacionados
by the
con el trabajo del personal de la
immigration control office staff and
oficina de control de inmigración y
now he says and the accused was informed
ahora dice y se le informó al acusado
that he should be sent out of the kingdom,
que Debería ser enviado fuera del reino
which led the accused to believe that he
lo que le llevó al acusado a creer que
could leave the kingdom within 48
se podría marchar fuera del reino en 48
hours, or as if they made him believe,
horas O sea como que le hicieron creer
according to his account  that they were going to throw him out of
según cuenta él que lo iban a largar de
Thailand in 48 hours he was going to leave The
Tailandia en 48 horas se iba a pirar El
police officer nicknamed James bon
oficial de policía apodado James bon le
asked the accused to sign the
pidió al acusado que firmara el
document and told him that if the accused
documento y le dijo que si el acusado
cooperated in the search for the
cooperaba la búsqueda de persona
missing person he would be transported out
desaparecida sería transportado fuera
of the kingdom and he believed it to be maybe
del reino y él lo creyó ser a lo mejor
a colloquial conversation in which
una conversación coloquial en la que que
maybe he would tell him you sign here it will
a lo mejor él le diga tú firma aquí que
go inside you a couple of that's what he
te va ir dentro un par de eso es lo que
is saying Daniel took Mr. JB and
está contando Daniel llevó al señor jb y
the rest of the officials on August 5,
al resto de funcionarios el 5 de agosto
2023 by pointing out the places where
de 2023 al señalar los lugares donde eh
the deceased's organs were disposed of
fueron desechados los órganos del
then the police officer
difunto luego el oficial de policía
took the accused back to the
llevó al acusado de regreso a la
Cangan police station On
estación de policía de cangan El 6 de
August 6, 2023, the police personnel
agosto de 2023 el personal de policía
took the accused to make a
llevó al acusado para realizar un
report to make the
informe para realizar la declaración de
plea he asked to meet with an
culpabilidad pidió reunirse con un
interpreter and a lawyer but he has not been
intérprete y un abogado pero no ha
able to contact them because the
podido contactarlos debido a que la
person from the investigation office
persona de la oficina de investigación
has prevented him from having access to it, in other words, he
le ha impedido tener acceso a ello o sea
says that on the 6th they did not let him have either a
dice que el día 6 no lo dejaron tener ni
lawyer or an interpreter what a lie because
abogado ni intérprete que Mentira porque
the statement is already coming the lawyer is coming
la declaración ya viene viene el abogado
No, but well, exactly, he has all
no pero bueno exactamente tiene todas
the evidence on the final page and the police
las pruebas página final y la policía lo
dismantled everything as if to say boom, with
desmontado todo como diciendo zasca con
all the lies, not to his face he was like, oh
todas las mentiras no a su cara se quedó
my God, why lie about
como diciendo madre mía porque mentir en
something that is verifiable because I
una cosa que es comprobable porque
understand lying in a fight, but about
entiendo mentir en la pelea pero en una
something like that that is verifiable and
cosa como esa que es comprobable y
putting yourself against the authority, what are you going to do?
ponerte en contra de la autoridad que va
Look, because the police have
[__] de si no Mira porque la policía ha
said from the beginning, the police said,
dicho desde el principio la policía dijo
this is a liar By the book, as if to
este es un mentiroso Por libro por como
say, he is a liar since he is born,
diciendo es un mentiroso desde que nace
more or less as if to say, believing in his
más o menos como diciendo é creer en su
own lie because they are
propio Mentira porque están
used to lying, then believing
acostumbrados a mentir entonces creer
that the lie, others are going to believe
que la mentira los demás la van a creer
their lies because they are
en sus mentiras porque están
used to it, but he doesn't realize
acostumbrados pero él no se da cuenta
that they are lying in front of an
que están mintiendo delante de un
investigating police officer, it would be common.
policía de investigación sería habitual
If the Thai police want to get
Si la policía tailandesa quiere sacar
a statement, they would tell a
una declaración que le hagan una menti
big lie to the alleged suspect. Yes, it is normal because
rejilla al supuesto Sí es normal porque
their technique, the technique so that
la técnica de ellos la técnica para que
you can sing things, but when they go
tú puedes cantar cosas pero cuando van
to court it is a thing of nonsense, it does not
en tribunal es una cosa de tonterías no
affect them, they know perfectly well that this
afecta ellos saber perfectamente que eso
is the technique that any
es la técnica de que cualquier
criminal can use words so
delincuente puede utilizan palabas como
that you sing, not of things to
para que tú cantes no de de cosas para
deceive you like that.  more or less but the
engañarle así más o menos pero la
technique that they use after
técnica lo que utilizan ellos después el
Mr. yb told him to collaborate in the
señor yb le dijo que colaborara en la
search for his missing friend that if he
búsqueda de su amigo desaparecido que si
collaborated he would be sent out of the
colaboraba se le enviaría fuera del
kingdom the interpreter did not read the content
reino el intérprete no leyó el contenido
of the note that is given to the evaluation
de la nota que se le da a la evaluación
so he listened first before signing
Así que escuchó primero antes de firmar
or in other words he says no it was not
o sea que dice que que no no se lo
read to him in Spanish what he did not understand is what it
leyeron en español lo que no entendió es
means no on August 7,
lo que viene a decir no el 7 de agosto
2023 the inspection office official
del 23 el funcionario de la oficina de
appeared at the
inspección se presentó en el tribunal de
provincial court Mr. Jam bon assumed the
la provincia el sñr Jam bon asumió el
role of interpreter with the help of
papel de intérprete con la ayuda del
Mr. aná as the accused's lawyer on
Señor aná como abogado del acusado el 16
August 16, 2023 police officers
de agosto del 23 los agentes de policía
went to Kosamui Island Prison
se trasladaron a la prisión de la isla
to interrogate the accused in
de kosamui para interrogar al acusado en
connection with a knife used in
relación con un arma blanca utilizado en
the attack and then it should be remembered that
el ataque y luego se debe recordar que
on October 19, 2023 the
el 19 de octubre del 23 el personal de
investigation staff notified about the
la investigación notificó sobre la
request for additional information the
solicitud de información adicional el
accused contacted the
acusado se puso en contacto con el
translator and the lawyer but he did not
traductor y el abogado pero no estuvo de
agree with the people who were
acuerdo con las personas que le fueron
assigned to him yes he did not want to sign he says he
asignadas sí no quiso firmar dice
confessed that the stage of  the investigation
confesó que la etapa de la investigación
because he was deceived and was induced
debido a que fue engañado y fue inducido
to make a statement by the
a hacer una declaración por la
investigator the
investigador el personal de
investigation staff did not inform him about his
investigación no le informó sobre su
rights did not provide him with
derechos no le proporcionó asesoramiento
legal advice that's what he said eh Well at
legal eso es lo que dijo eh Bueno en
this point basically we see the
este punto básicamente vemos la
difference maybe in some things
diferencia a lo mejor en algunas cosas
that here in Spain in Europe
que aquí en España en Europa
would work differently And it is that an
funcionarían de otra manera Y es que un
accused can complain about his
acusado se puede quejar de de sus
human rights Oh it is that they have
derechos humanos Ay es que han
violated This they have made me declare
incumplido Esto me han hecho declaras
without a lawyer they have done to me So I don't know
sin abogado me han hecho Entonces no sé
to what extent what they
yo hasta qué punto qué
think murder and also with all
opinarán asesinato y además con todas
the ballots these things are done to him
las papeletas se le hagan estas cosas
to get a statement because here
para sacarle una declaración porque aquí
in Europe maybe we have a lot of
en Europa a lo mejor tenemos muchas
nonsense no something else would be
tonterías no otra cosa sería una
extortion a threat by the
extorsión una amenaza por parte de la
police because then they can
policía porque entonces ahí te puede
force you to declare something that is not the
obligar a declarar una cosa que no sea
truth Look this is
la verdad Mira esto es la primera
his first statement and the second because the
declaración de él y la segunda porque la
first one has an extension and as you can see it
primera hay una ampliación y como veis
is signed by Daniel Sánchez or rather and
está firmado por Daniel Sánchez o sea y
here are the lawyer the interpreter
aquí están el abogado el intérprete
you can translate it but you can translate it
podéis traducirlo pero podéis traducirlo
if you want with the mobile it is the lawyer the
si queréis con el móvil es el abogado el
interpreter This is the first
intérprete Esta es la primera
statement that also where if you
declaración que además donde si os
look at the drawing  Oh yeah And he said that they
fijáis el dibujito Ah sí Y él dijo que
are all in agreement, understood everything and
están Todo de acuerdo entendido todo y
everything and it has been signed on all pages
tod y se ha firmado en todas las páginas
eh Not only on that one But then he
eh No solamente en esa Pero luego él
lied about that by
mentio de eso
lawyers and by and by
esa par abogados y por y por por
lawyers and by everyone I mean it's
abogados y por por todos o sea está
signed by everyone it's like he accused
firmado por todos es como él acusó
later because he didn't remember what he
después porque no se acordaba lo que
had signed he didn't remember what he
había firmado no se acordaba lo que
had said I mean it's like in his
había dicho o sea es como que en su
head he has so many lies the problem
cabeza tiene tantas mentiras lo problema
is the problem he didn't know from which part
es el problema él no sabía de qué parte
what he had lied it's not like let's
lo que había mentido no es como que a
see at what moment I lied And now
ver cuál qué momento he mentido Y ahora
what I do is like they are taking
qué hago es como que van desmontando
things apart it's crazy there me there what I
cosas una locura ahí yo ahí lo que
think is that at the beginning he doesn't lie
pienso es que él al principio no miente
as much as when they start to advise him
tanto como cuando empiezan a aconsejarle
you have to declare this you have to
tienes que declarar esto tienes que
follow this path he at the beginning well would
seguir este camino él al principio pues
say I'm going to cooperate I'm going to tell the
diría yo voy a colaborar voy a decir la
truth they caught me or whatever this
verdad me han trincado o lo que sea esta
part is said in the sentence page
parte la dicen en la sentencia la página
21 it says when the accused confesses the
21 dice cuando el acusado confiesa el
court can pass sentence without
tribunal puede dictar sentencia sin
needing to present more evidence in
necesidad de presentar más pruebas de
accordance with the code of
acuerdo con el código del procedimiento
criminal procedure article 176 and it is accepted as a
penal artículo 176 y se acepta como un
fact that the accused committed  the crime
hecho que el acusado cometió el delito
mentioned in the accusation I mean, it's not
mencionado en la acusación O sea no es
like here in Spain where they say that the
como aquí en España que dicen que la
accusation is worthless, but with
acusación no vale De nada si no que con
evidence that is worth it. Well, according to
pruebas que la valen Pues según recoge
the sentence according to the Thai penal code,
la sentencia según el código penal
the accused can be convicted
tailandés se puede condenar al acusado
simply with his own statement, it is
simplemente con su propia declaración es
very important, that is what he calls an oral trial. It
muy importante eso lo llama juicio oral
is super important that in the case that the
es superimportante que en el caso que el
judge considers it appropriate, under his
juez considerase oportuno que Bajo su
subjectivity, he considers that he has to
subjetividad él considera que tiene que
condemn, he has the rights of the law to do so
condenar tiene las de la ley para
if he wants, even without more
hacerlo si quiere incluso sin más
evidence or presenting anything, I mean, he
pruebas ni presentar nada o sea te lo
tells you very clearly when the accused
dice bien claro cuando el acusado
confesses, the court can pronounce
confiesa el tribunal puede dichar
sentence without the need to present more
sentencia sin necesidad de presentar más
evidence in accordance with the code of
pruebas de acuerdo con el código del
criminal procedure, article 176, it is
procedimiento penal artículo 176 se
accepted as a fact, the accused committed
acepta como un hecho el acusado cometió
the crime mentioned in the accusation.
el delito mencionado en la acusación
Yesterday I spoke with the head of
ayer mismo hablé con el jefe de
investigation, a detail that he gave me
investigación un detalle que él me dio
because I said when Ju condemns that one,
porque yo dije cuando Ju condena a ese
in that case of Daniel Sancho, not of
en ese caso de Daniel Sancho no de
capital carena and then with mutated he says
carena capital y después con mutada dice
you know why it is commuted and he
ustedes saben Por qué está conmutada y
told me because he collaborated, okay, that's what we
me dijo porque él colaboró vale eso es
know, he collaborated to help the
lo que sabemos colaboró para ayudar la
investigation, blah blah blah blah and
investigación bla bla bla bla bla y
then I said if there was that part
entonces yo dije si no había esa parte
of collaboration what would happen he told me 100%
de colaboración qué pasaría me dijo 100%
capital punishment 100% and that's what Enens
pena capital 100% y eso es lo que enens
saved and then I said it's possible that the
salvó y entonces yo dije es posible que
prosecution had doubts about some evidence he
fiscalía tenía dudas alg unas pruebas me
told me in our system we don't
dijo en sistema de nosotros no
work what you mean
trabajamos lo que tú quieres decir
when we already have all the
cuando nosotros tenemos ya todas las
evidence tying Daniel Sancho because we already have the
pruebas atando a Daniel Sancho porque ya
puzzle everything in place
tenemos los en puzle todo encajado
then he ordered all that evidence to the
entonces ordenó todao esa la prueba en
prosecution and says that normally the prosecution
fiscalía y dice que normalmente fiscalía
if they don't agree he says it's a
si no están de acuerdo dice es un filtro
very important filter saying that they are going to talk to
muy importante dic que van a hablar con
the police saying no you don't have to
la policía diciendo no no me tienen que
bring me the most conclusive evidence but at
traer la prueba más contundentes pero
that moment he had so so conclusive
ese momento tenía tan tan contundentes
in all the evidence the prosecution didn't
en todas las pruebas la fiscalía no tia
doubt not even the moment Which is why he says that it is
duda ni el momento Por lo cual dice que
elevated to the judge not to present
se eleva al juez no para presentar
before the judge and he told me normally
delante en juez y él me dijo normalmente
when the judge has already received everything and if there was no
cuando el juez ya recibido todo y si no
complaint from the judges at that
había queja de parte de los jueces en
moment he says that we
ese ese momento dice que nosotros ya
are already like we have done an
estamos como hemos hecho un trabajo
excellent job with which in Ju when you see
excelente con lo cual en Ju cuando ves
that it is a job well done on the part of the
que es un trabajo bien hecho de parte de
police well done on the part of the prosecutor
policía bien hecho de parte de fiscal
then he only needs to
entonces solamente necesita Pues
interrogate Daniel and that's it Then he already had
interrogar a Daniel y punto Entonces ya
very clear with the evidence from the
tenía ya muy claro con la prueba de la
prosecution's presentation and this is what I
presentación de fiscalía y la Esto es lo
told you before the testimony of
que te he dicho antes del testimonio de
rich raica la la of the bungalow says
de rica de raica la la del bungaló Dice
Miss Raica Chin owner of the
la señorita raica chin propietaria de la
villa reported that a
villa informó que se reservó una
room was reserved in the accommodation number
habitación en del alojamiento la número
5 as of August 1, 23
5 a partir del 1 de agosto del 23
available online a motorcycle arrived
disponible online una motocicleta llegó
at the room with only one person with
a la habitación con una sola persona con
a backpack and a handbag is where he
una mochila y una bolsa de mano es donde
carried the knives and so on told her
llevaba los cuchillos y demás le dijo
that he came to cangan to study
que venía a cangan para estudiar
Thai the room is a
tailandés la habitación es un espacio
separate space that includes a living room
separado que incluye una sala de estar
a kitchen and a bathroom the kitchen is
una cocina y un baño la cocina está
equipped for cooking you see they said it was
equipada para cocinar ves que decían que
not equipped well she says that it
no estaba equipada pues ella dice que sí
is equipped for cooking inside the
está equipada para cocina dentro de la
room there is a medium sized refrigerator
habitación hay un refrigerador de tamaño
for the service of customers
mediano para el servicio de los clientes
the witness never saw another person
el testigo nunca vio a otra persona que
come to that room do you remember the
viniera a esa habitación os acordáis la
theories that came out the first
de teorías que salieron los primeros
days about a third person and if
días sobre una tercera persona y que si
someone was there with Daniel and went alone left
alguien allí con Daniel é iba solo salió
Only until he entered with Edwin and then
Solo hasta que entraba con Edwin y luego
Daniel left alone and without Erwin left and
ya salió Daniel solo y sin salió Erwin y
the one from the call says Miss
la del call Dice la señorita
Kanan owner of the cor  bungalov
kanan propietaria del cor bungalov
stated that on August 2, 2023
declaró que el 2 de Agosto de 2023
around 7 the accused entered
alrededor de las 7 el acusado entró en
the store and asked to buy a callay
la tienda y le pidió comprar un callay
the witness stated that he was not
el testigo declaró que no estaba
selling but renting the accused
vendiendo sin alquilando el acusado
placed $ 1,000 on the counter and then
colocó $1,000 en el mostrador y luego se
went to the beach, meaning he gave him
dirigió a la playa O sea que le soltó
the 1,000 and went to get a callar
los 1,000 y se fue a por un callar
taking the witness's red callar
llevándose el callar de color rojo del
to the shore and now he says
testigo hacia la orilla y ahora dice
later on August 3,
posteriormente el día 3 de agosto de
2023 around 6 in the morning the
2023 alrededor de las 6 de la mañana la
witness saw a person rowing with the
testigo vio a una persona remando con el
witness's callar in the sea near the
ká del testigo en el mar cerca de la
beach, meaning she had it but that they
playa O sea que la tenía pero que lo
saw him the next day already throwing a calla at
vieron al día siguiente ya tirando cuo a
7 in the morning The only thing missing was
las 7 de la mañana Es que solo faltaba
a camera focusing on the beach and that he could
una cámara enfocando para la playa y que
also be seen in the calla throwing
se le viera también en el calla tirando
things that he was condemned carried
las cosas que estaba condenad llevado
like entering leaving entering leaving
como entrando saliendo entrando saliendo
with the entire camera of all the ledón
con toda la cámara de de todo el ledón
recording it at that moment I think that
grabándolo en ese momento yo creo que
she forgot everything that was on the
ella olvidado todo lo que había en la
camera I think that she did not know at any
cámara yo creo que no lo sabía de ningún
time Eh  No, I don't think so, I do
momento Eh no yo creo que no yo creo que
n't think he knew, eh. He had no [ __ ] idea, if he
no lo sabía eh No tenía ni [__] idea si
hadn't done what he did. And with all
no hubiese hecho lo que hizo Y con toda
the footage that he went out to eat
la película que de de que se fue a comer
and all that, I think he thought it
y tal yo creo que se creía que aquello
was kind of wild, which surprised me
era medio salvaje lo que me extrañaba
a lot because in Thailand,
mucho porque si en Tailandia toda parte
the whole camera, how could they not, I don't know,
la cámara Cómo no no van a no sé
observe that the camera was recording, they are
observar que la cámara estaba grabando
expensive, I mean, it's not like you and
son un de caro o sea no es decir que tú
the cameras see him come in and
coas y las cámaras le vean entrar y
go, well, and he's pretending, no, no,
salir bueno y él está disimulando no no
the videos have to be a spectacle
los vídeos tien que ser un espectáculo
because he goes out with the bag, he comes in, you can
porque va con la borsa sale entra se le
also see when he is carrying more weight when he leaves
ve además cuando va más cargado al salir
and when he is carrying no weight when he comes in, I mean, it's
y cuando va sin peso al entrar o sea es
the cameras at
las cámar a las
9:59 p.m. it shows the accused carrying two
2159 muestra el acusado llevando dos
garbage bags to the
bolsas de basura para e charlas en el
disposal area behind the
área de desecho detrás de la tienda del
Crisal Day store, that is, in Gu Vill at
crisal day o sea en el en el gu vill a
8:33 p.m. the used bag is seen
las 8:33 de la tarde se observa el ag
walking with a black garbage bag
usado caminando con una bolsa de basura
and carrying a backpack towards the
negra y llevando una mochila hacia el
disposal area behind the store
punto de deshecho detrás de la tienda
where he left the black garbage bag that he was
dónde dejó la bolsa de basura negra que
carrying the backpack. It was observed that later  he
llevaba la mochila se observó que luego
hid the bag in a bush near
escondió la bolsa en un arbusto cerca
the dumpster after the
del contenedor de basura después de
accused walked towards the beach undressed
acusado caminó hacia la playa se desnudó
and returned to the room at 11:10
y regresó al la habitación a las 11:10
the accused was seen walking with two
se observó al acusado caminando con dos
white garbage bags from the bugin
bolsas de basura blancas del Hotel bugin
Villa Hotel that he took to throw away at the
Villa que llevo a tirar en el punto de
garbage point behind the Cristi
basura detrás de la tienda del Cristi
day store and then he picked up two
day y luego recogió dos bolsas de
black plastic bags that he had thrown away
plástico negras que había tirado
previously and put them away the backpack
anteriormente y las guardó la mochila
that he had hidden carrying a backpack
que había escondido llevando una mochila
the accused left towards the beach J at
el acusado salió hacia la playa J a las
11:41 and the accused walked along one side of
11:41 y el acusado caminó por un lado de
the beach then returned to the bu Villa but
la playa luego regresó al bu Villa pero
without the backpack he can't imagine that he is being
sin la mochila no se imagina que lo
recorded nor for [ __ ] But how is he going to
están grabando ni de coña Pero cómo va a
believe that he is being recorded if the guy
creer que lo están grabando si el tío
hid the backpack I mean if he knows that they
escondió la mochila O sea si sabe que lo
are recording him why is he hiding it noog
están grabando para que la esconde noog
hid the backpack in the bush the
escondid la mochila en el arbusto las
black bags that he takes out of the garbage and he puts
bolsas negras que él saca de la basura y
them back in c he takes it somewhere
se y se las vuelve a meter c se la lleva
else it would be something important that
para otro lado sería algo importante que
he would say Uy this here smells bad or or they are
él diría Uy esto aquí huele mal o o lo
going to see it man No we are not going to talk about the
van a ver tío No no vamos a hablar de la
statement what do you think is brutal
declaración qué os parece que es brutal
My impression is that it is scripted.
yo mi impresión es que es guionizada O
Meaning that he declares what they advise him to
sea que él declara lo que le aconsejan
declare. But how is it going to be scripted and I
declarar Pero cómo va a ser guionizado y
'll explain why. If the defense
te voy a explicar por qué Si la defensa
brings a witness that one of the
lleva a un testigo que lo llevó uno de
ones brought, the other one didn't go, but it was one
los que fue el otro no fue pero fue uno
to say that he had suffered harassment from
para decir que había sufrido acoso de
Ewin Arrieta, that Ewin Arrieta had
ewin Arrieta que ewin Arrieta lo tenía
sexually harassed him, that Ewin Arrieta
acosado sexualmente que ewin Arrieta lo
had. That was the witness that the
había Ese fue el testigo que llevó la
defense brought, then it was Ivan Velasco
defensa luego fue el Iván Velasco
also to tell this story that was
también para contar esa película que se
put together that Win Arriet was a person
montó de que Win arriet era una persona
who sexually harassed you and then
que te acosaba sexualmente y luego llega
this one arrives and what he testifies is that he didn't
este y en lo que testifica es que él no
even know that Ewin wanted
sabía ni que ewin quería relaciones
sexual relations with him. Up until now, it didn't
sexuales con él Hasta el momento no
fit, that he caught the lies
encajaba eso lo ha pillado las mentiras
right away. When a legal team
enseguida cuando un equipo jurídico
has to prepare a defense, they have to
tiene que preparar una defensa tiene que
put everything there is on the table. If
poner sobre la mesa todo lo que hay si
you're going to say that you didn't have any
tú vas a decir que tú no tenías ninguna
relationship with this man, there can't be
relación con este hombre no pueden
messages telling him Kari,
existir unos mensajes diciéndole Kari te
I'm waiting for you here. I can't wait to see you. You
estoy esperando aquí Qué ganas de verte
don't know, I mean, But Javi, from the
No sabes o sea Pero Javi desde al
beginning, when he spoke to the police,
principio cuando él habló con la policía
from the moment  when he caught him and everything
desde el momento cuando le pilló y todo
he said that yes he had the
él dijo que sí que tenía la reacción
sexual reaction with Edwin in Spain I choose some
sexual con Edwin en España elijo unos
lawyers who have prepared this for
abogados que han preparado esto durante
months how in your head can you say now
meses en qué cabeza cabe que digas ahora
no no no no we didn't have
no no que va nosotros no teníamos
any relationship you say that but churr
ninguna relación tú di eso pero churr es
the witnesses that they carried if they
que los Testigos que llevaban si
carried even a witness of
llevaron hasta hasta un testigo de
sexual abuse the same defense that
abusos sexuales la misma defensa que la
did everything wrong they themselves that they
hecho todo mal ellos mismos que la han
put her in the cage in aguj while they
metido en la jaula en aguj mientras que
walk around on TV saying that the
se pasean por la tele diciendo que la
police are a bungler what I don't
policía es una chapua lo que yo no
understand how the defense had one
entiendo como la defensa llevaba una
line and Daniel had a totally
línea y Daniel llevaba otra totalmente
different one why I mean what sense does it make
diferente por qué O sea qué sentido
that the defense has one line and has
tiene que la defensa lleve una línea y
another we are going to defend the
lleve otra vamos a defender la aula de
glass classroom we are going to defend that you finished
cristal vamos a defender que te acaba
that you had a relationship and
que habías tenido una relación y llega
the guy arrives with his balls acos and says that there is no
el tío con sus cojon acos y dice que no
relationship that he had no
hay relación que no tenía ninguna
connection with even a [ __ ] for
vinculación con hasta una felación por
money yes I think that in ruling
dinero eso sí Yo creo que en fallo que
Daniel told the truth from the beginning
Daniel dijo la verdad desde el principio
and then they want to dismantle the
y luego ellos quieren desmontar la
truth and he hasn't been able to How can you get it
verdad y no ha podido Cómo puedes [__]
and it may seem like a good idea to you that your
y te puede parecer buena idea que tu
client alleges that suddenly it is
cliente alegue que de repente es
fortuitous to meet you already  there on the trip
fortuito encontrarte ya allí en el viaje
when we are talking about these
cuando estamos hablando de que esta
people having taken a room as a
gente habían cogido un habitación en
couple Although then the CA to another who
pareja Aunque luego el CA a otra que
was also a couple but how do you
también era en pareja pero cómo te
think it's a good idea for your client to say that
parece buena idea que tu cliente diga
suddenly he finds that
eso que de repente se encuentra con que
the other becomes aggressive stalker
el otro se pone agresivo acosador le
asks him for a [ __ ] when they are two
pide una felación cuando son dos
people who have already traveled the
personas que ya han recorrido la
Iberian Peninsula on their honeymoon without
Península ibérica de viaje de novios sin
so much technicality or rather without focusing on
tanto tecnicismo o sea sin centrarnos en
how the victim's sentence tells it
cómo lo cuenta la sentencia del señor
I will make the drawing that Daniel
víctima te hago el dibujo que Daniel
captures they go to the bungalow Will you can
plasma ellos van al bungaló el Will se
see that he asks him why we are going to that
ve que le pregunta por qué vamos a ese
bungalow and Will says no it's that I'm already
bungaló y el Will dice no es que yo ya
staying in this one because I'm going to
yo me estoy quedando en este porque voy
record the cooking videos in this one in
a grabar los vídeos de cocina en este en
this bungalow they enter the bungalow And
este bungaló entran en el bungaló Y en
instead of sitting in the living room they go to
vez de sentarse en el salón se van a la
bed because he says they are in bed
cama porque dice que están en la cama
which I also don't understand if I'm going to
cosa que tampoco entiendo si voy a
talk about business what the hell hao the bed
hablar de negocio qué [__] hao la cama
but anyway and now the two of them sitting in
pero bueno y ahora sentados los dos en
bed Daniel tells him that well that
la cama Daniel le dice que bueno que que
since he had promised to give him some money
como le tenía prometido darle un dinero
and such that he had taken him that bungalow
y tal que le había llevado ese bungaló
well to record the cooking videos
pues para grabar los vídeos de cocina
that  I don't know what I was going to record because there
que no sé que iba a grabar porque no
was no food to buy, I don't know what I was going to
haby a comprar comida yo no sé que iba a
cook, but well, I wanted to cook something,
cocinar Pero bueno algo quería cocinar
the fruit that was already cut, the
la frutita que ya venía cortada j la
watermelon, because he says no. So I
sandía porque le dice no Entonces le
tell him that I want to record a video
digo que que Quiero grabar un video
ad for such and such and he tells me that it was
anuncio de tal y él me dice a mí que era
false that he was not going to help me
falso que él no me iba a ayudar
financially and at that moment I
económicamente y en ese momento yo me
get angry and I did it out of the room, get out of
mosqueo y lo he hecho de la habitación
here, get out, go and at that
fuera de aquí fuera vete y en ese
moment he tells me okay, right
momento me dice que bueno que aquí alado
here next door, he'll help me if I give him a
aquí al lado que me ayuda si le hago una
[ __ ], if he wants money, I should give him a
felación que si quiere dinero que le
[ __ ], that's what he says, eh.
haga una felación es lo que dice él eh
So I get pissed off because he tries to
Entonces yo me cabreo porque él intenta
strangle me, he throws himself triangularly and
estrangular me se tira triangular y
then I punch him, he
entonces yo le pego un puñetazo él se
trips over the door, it's not that I
tropieza con la puerta no es que yo lo
throw him over, he trips, it's just if what
tire del se tropieza es solo si lo que
we have said, that perhaps what many
hemos dicho que quizás lo que mucha
people say, let's see if Edwin
gente dice a ver si Edwin autod
dismembered himself, you find it
descuartizaba a sí mismo os parece
funny, but what is what he declared? I
gracioso pero que es lo que ha declarado
think he really didn't give a damn,
yo creo que se le ha sudado los [__]
judgment, sincerely, I think it has been
juicio sinceramente yo creo que se ha
said if I go here anyway  All my
dicho si yo de toas forma voy aquí Toda
life No seriously if not And now I'll
la vida No en serio que si no Y ahora te
tell you one thing how do you raise an
digo yo una cosa cómo planteas un
appeal based on what if the T what he
recurso basado en qué si el T lo que ha
declared in the trial is that the other
declarado en el juicio es que el otro lo
financed him now how do you raise because
financiaba ahora cómo planteas porque ya
what's the point of the coconuts the
de qué me vale lo de los cocos los
raincoats in the garbage and it's I
chubasqueros de la basura y es me da
sincerely don't care and then yes yes with
igual sinceramente y luego ya si si con
all that lie believe that what he says is true that he
toda la mentira esa créete que es verdad
did without a lawyer that
lo que cuenta de que fue sin abogado de
but if you're telling me that Win
que pero si me estás diciendo que Win
strangled art I'm going to believe the other is there
trangular arte te voy a creer lo otro
any other statement that you have
hay alguna declaración más que hayas
read or in that half of the sentence
leído os en esa mitad de la sentencia
there are many or I mean there's the police thing What
hay muchas o sea está lo de la policía
happens is that in order to break it down
Lo que pasa que así para poder desglosar
here is that they are super long things
la aquí es que son super largas cosas
for example interesting Well, when you
por ejemplo interesantes Pues que cuando
find the pants and the
encuentras los pantalones y los
underwear inside that people were
calzoncillos dentro de que la gente se
wondering how is it possible that there is no
preguntaba cómo es posible que no haya
blood that there is nothing Well then
sangre que no haya nada Bueno pues
when they open the bags where the
cuando abren las bolsas donde está la
clothes are the bags
ropa las bols
Ah inside the bungalow they would
yer Ah dentro del bungaló se pondría a
also try to clean the clothes
intentar también la ropa limpiarla lo
as much as possible I imagine it says that the clothes
máximo posible imagino dice que la ropa
go what is the t-shirt and the
va lo que es la camiseta y los
pants go  Inside some bags
pantalones van dentro de de unas bolsas
soaked the phrase is in foamy soap
empapados la frase es en jabón espumoso
and all the evidence from the bags
y todas las pruebas tanto de las bolsas
on Daniel's body. The pieces that
en cuerpo dein Las piezas que
were dismembered all have Daniel's DNA.
descuartizó todo tiene ADN de